Never forget why you are the church.
Turn your Bibles to Romans chapter 12.
If you happen, Lord, say amen.
Romans chapter 12.
This morning, we're going to be concluding This
series within a series of the impact of the gospel.
And just to remind you, I
want you to understand the gospel impacts every single part of your life.
When you become a new creation in
Christ, by receiving the good news that Jesus lived,
died, and rose again just like we sang, there
is a change made.
I want us to think about something.
Let's say that you have an old vehicle that doesn't do anything but give you problems.
Anyone here anyone here ever had that kind of vehicle.
You had a vehicle, you just may just get problem at the problem at the problem, right?
I mean, this thing has all kinds of leaks, the transmission.
It misses, the seats are ripped up, the power windows
are stuck, the AC doesn't work.
The timing chain is ticking.
There's a nail in the tire.
This vehicle is more likely to leave you stranded
than to get you where you're trying to go.
Does anyone know what I'm talking about here?
Amen.
I mean, this thing is all but useless.
for anything of worth.
So you decide to do something about it.
You decide that you're going to invest in a new vehicle.
This amen.
This
one has all the bells and all the whistles.
I'm talking about, it's the best of the best.
It's got the power, everything, got the big screen,
got the nice engine, new upgraded everything.
You sacrificed so much to purchase this brand new vehicle.
Let me ask you something.
What happens when your new vehicle begins that like your old vehicle?
Well, ain't that just patient?
No, be for real.
What happens?
Well, brother, we just pray.
No, stop it.
What happens when your new vehicle begins?
All of a sudden it begins to leak oil?
It starts to get a lifter ticket.
The AC starts blowing cold.
It's the dead of summer.
It begins to be broken down more than it drives.
How would you react to this?
This is a brand new vehicle.
This is not your own vehicle.
You would be outraged, absolutely flabbergasted.
You would feel bamboozled and deceived.
Somebody would have to pay.
This is a new vehicle.
A new vehicle does not do these kind of things.
Y'all get what I'm throwing down right here.
Here's the thing.
Why would we be so angry?
Well, hear me today because we understand the concept of new.
We get that new is different.
We understand it.
There's certain things that come with new,
but for too many, we forget what new means the
moment it comes to the things of God.
See, we want heaven.
We want Jesus.
We want fellowship, and we want to be identified with a growing
church, yet we still desire to live
that old life.
See, this mindset, hear me.
This mindset is completely and utterly incompatible
with salvation through Jesus Christ.
When he makes us new, he gives us everything and
all that we need to live in newness of life.
And the greatest of this is the Holy Spirit.
And this is where grace gifts come into play.
Ive heard so many times.
Well, you know, I just, I don't really know what I can do or
I don't know if I'm used to anything.
Yeah, I know the Lord, but I still don't know enough.
I don't know enough to take this step in ministry.
I don't know enough to be able to teach a kids' class.
I don't know enough or I don't I'm not close enough.
Listen, that excuse is okay for a split second.
You know what, you just told yourself?
You need to understand a Holy Spirit is able
to teach you and to remind you the things that you've been taught,
is able to discern that which is right from wrong.
You don't have to wait to become a mature Christian to serve.
You know how you become a mature Christian?
You serve.
Y'all with me this morning?
I'm feeling pretty good about this.
You serve.
This is where grace gifts come into play.
When God saved you, he gifted you for
the purpose of his glory and the building up of his church.
This changes the way we interact
in every part of our lives.
So let's look at our text yet again, and we're going
to study the last grace gift mentioned here by the apostle Paul.
Romans chapter 12, verse 6 through 8.
If you're there to say, read.
Having then gifts differing according to the grace
that is given to us where the prophecy, let us prophesy
according to the proportion of faith or ministry,
that service, let us wait on our ministering, or he that teacheth
on teaching, or he that exhorteth, that's encouragement, on
exhortation, he that giveth, let him do it with simplicity,
he that ruleth, that is to lead with diligence,
he that showeth mercy with cheerfulness.
Well, looking at this theme,
the impact of the gospel in personal ministry.
Let's pray, Father, I thank you for your word.
I thank you for just a time of worship that we have.
God, I pray we just continue worshiping you through your word.
God through the life that we live according to your
word, God and the conviction of the Holy Spirit.
So God, I pray that we understand the change that
has been made in our life.
And God, I pray that we manifest that to those around
us, God, especially those of the household of faith.
And we thank you, we love you.
In Jesus name, pray.
And everybody said?
Amen.
Today we are looking at the spiritual gift and grace gift of
mercy, the gift of mercy.
It is interesting that Paul mentions
this gift last.
And to really understand this, we have to know what mercy means.
That word mercy in Romans 8 refers to, it
means to show mercy, obviously, but that also
means to show pity too.
Now, you can find this term all over scriptures
both in how God interacts with us and
how we are to interact with others.
But I want to give you an important thought regarding
the gift of mercy.
Mercy is a crucial and foundational
part of God's relationship to us.
Let me say it again.
Mercy is a crucial and foundational part of
God's relationship to us.
What do I mean by this?
Well, biblical mercy can be defined
as God's faithful commitment to his people.
despite his people's unfaithfulness to him.
Let me simplify this even more for you this morning.
Mercy describes us not receiving what
we rightfully deserve.
See, we deserve death and
eternal torment and hell for our sins, yet because God
is merciful, he allows us through Jesus to
be saved and delivered from that.
The Bible says that he seals us, he keeps
us by the power of God.
Listen, ever since you've been born again.
You haven't been perfect, but yet God has still saved you.
That's mercy.
Understand that a
non-merciful God would save you, then you mess up and he'd
be done and do away with you.
No, no, no.
God is a merciful God.
When he saves you, he keeps you, he seals you.
He gives you daily mercy.
That is mercy.
Now let's go further into this.
When we sin, again, God could simply just say, you know what, I'm
done with you, but however, his mercy that he is tied
to and his character and his promises.
He remains faithful to us, and we remain justified in his sight.
Now, I don't want to, I have to be very careful here because
when people here a preacher say that you can't
do anything to lose your salvation or God
gives you mercy no matter what, and that's all true,
they start to think, and immature believers say, oh,
well then my sin's not that bad.
Or you know what?
Oh, those plans that I made for tonight, maybe I can go.
Well, you know what?
Maybe that's sin that has me captive.
You know, hey, God gives me mercy.
So what does it matter?
Let me just tell you something.
This is not a license to sin.
Do we just partake in sin because
we can't, of course not.
We must live within the new and divine nature, that we are
now partakers in.
I need you to hear me.
If you are a born again believer, say amen.
All right, say a little bit louder, because that wasn't good enough.
Amen.
you were born again, believe it, say amen.
Okay.
If you're living in sin, You should be miserable.
A
believer cannot be joyful.
And rejoicing in anything but the Lord.
And sin is contrary to a holy God.
Therefore, if you are living in sin,
and you can do so, Ty, and I'm not saying that,
listen, sometimes we get calloused and it takes a good gospel
message or a good Bible study and or the Holy
Spirit to just punch us in the face just to say, hey, look, you're
going the wrong way, turn back.
But if you're living in sin and you're just
as joyful, you're just as good, you're not thinking nothing of it.
There's something wrong.
You
know, there's a condition.
Where, uh, when you're
born with this condition, you can't feel pain.
And so what happens, and
I don't know what the conditions call, but I was reading an article, watching a
video, I forget which one, about someone giving testimony to
their son was born with this condition and
could not feel pain at all, no matter.
I mean, it wasn't even a little pain.
There was no therapy to be done, just no pain at all.
Well, this particular condition.
Because I think there's a bunch of conditions that maybe have that included in there,
but this was like solely like this is this is not good.
And so what would happen is they would live their life and where
me and you stub our toe, we grab our foot
and we jump up and down and we scream and we holler and some of y'all say
bad words and you shouldn't, you should repent.
But either way, you stub your toe and it hurts.
This person would stub their toe and not know nothing of it.
They could just be walking around with a broken toe.
They go in and they
play football at school and they get tackled and break their collarbone.
They don't they don't they don't know anything of it.
because they can't feel pain.
This person's son
that had this condition.
Unfortunately, did not make it long.
Because eventually he
kept on getting hurt and hurt and you would never know because he didn't
say anything about it, and he ended up losing his life.
And you say, that's terrible and it is terrible.
But I want you to know something.
As believers.
that just because they, when they walk in sin
and, and they walk in sin and if there's no pain, what's going to happen
is you're going to begin to hurt yourself and not care.
You're going to begin to hurt others around you and just simply not care.
See, an unbeliever, what they do is they can live in sin and that's just their nature.
They're just doing what they've been born to do.
They've been they've been born their sin nature.
Therefore, they don't care.
And people say, well, there's good people that are lost.
Listen, there's none righteous, no, not one.
There's nobody good.
Listen, when you start to qualify what
goodness is, according to who God is, you realize very quickly, nobody's good.
They can do a few good deeds, but God is good.
Only through God can we obtain righteousness.
But listen, there's too many people walking around this world,
just not understanding that they spiritually stub their toe or
they're allowing sin to enter and hurt their lives.
Listen, we gotta have the conviction of the Holy Spirit.
I want to be so sensitive to my sin that it
doesn't take much to really tear me up.
Do you understand what I'm saying this morning?
But here, what I'm trying to say is
we have to realize this is not a license to sin.
We must live in that new divine nature.
We must understand this because it is the foundation of
how we are to interact with others as well.
So what does mercy look like one to another?
That word mercy can be translated from the Hebrew
and Greek to many English words.
And these words will help us understand the depth of what mercy means.
Words like kindness, loving
kindness, goodness, grace, favor, pity,
compassion, and steadfast love, all help explain
the act and gift of mercy.
And so to understand how this gift manifests
into our lives and the function of the church, we can look to
Jesus as the example.
In Matthew chapter 20, go ahead and turn there real quick.
Put your little marker in Romans 12 and turn to Matthew 20.
It's been a while since I made you turn to another text and I
can tell because some of y'all are like, I don't want to do that.
Hurry up.
1st book of the New Testament, Matthew Twain.
We're going to be in verses 29 through 34.
This is one of my, it's one of my favorite stories and every story
is my favorite story in the Bible.
In the Bible is good.
It's just good.
Matthew chapter 20, please hurry up.
Verse 29.
All right, if you're there, say I'm there.
Whoa, okay, easy now.
You there.
Matthew 20, verse 29 says this.
As they were leaving Jericho.
A large crowd followed him, this is Jesus.
And 2 blind men sitting by the road hearing
that Jesus was passing by, cried out, Lord, have
mercy on us, son of David.
The crowd sternly told them to be quiet, but they cried out all the more.
Lord, son of David, have mercy on us.
And Jesus stopped and called them and said, what do you want me to do for you?
They said to him, Lord, we want our eyes to be opened.
Mood with compassion.
Verse 34.
Jesus touched their eyes and immediately they regained their sight and
followed him.
I want you to remember this other truth right here.
The gift of mercy goes beyond human understanding and expectation.
The gift of mercy goes beyond human understanding
and expectation.
How do we understand human interaction, especially
intense and hurtful situations.
We love the Old Testament concept
of an eye for an eye.
You did me wrong.
I'm going to do you wrong.
You did this to me.
I'm going to do this to you.
Well, they had it coming.
They got what they deserved.
That's how we think about so many things in our life.
Let's think about this example, though, in Matthew 20.
We see Jesus leaving Jericho in a large crowd
following him.
All of a sudden, 2 blind men sitting on the road.
They heard Jesus and cried out to him.
Now, this requires some context here because
if you don't know the context, and this is just a cool story in God's
word, but let me give you some context.
In that time, blindness, especially,
but also other physical disabilities were attributed
to punishment for one sin.
If you are blind like these 2 men, you
are written off as social outcast and likely
reduced to a beggar on the streets.
We see this social norm and perspective
emphasized in John 91 through 3.
It says this as he passed by.
He saw a blind man from birth.
This person was blind from the time he was born.
And his disciples asked him, rabbi, who sinned?
This man or his parents that he would be born blind.
Jesus answered, it was neither that,
this man's sin nor his parents, but it was so that the works of God
might be displayed in him.
See, we see here, yet again, the social norms
of outcasting those like these 2 blind men.
No one had time for people like this.
They were an inconvenience.
Notice when a 2 blind men called
out for Jesus for mercy.
How did the multitude respond?
The crowd sternly told them to be quiet.
In other words, if you want to put this in our terms today.
They basically said, hush.
Jesus is busy.
We don't have time for you.
right now.
I believe this shows the greatest contrast
between the people and Jesus.
What did Jesus do?
Well, in Matthew 20 again, verse 31 through 32, the crowd sternly told them to be quiet.
But they cried out all the more.
Lord, son of David, have mercy on us.
And Jesus stopped and
called them and said, what do you want me to do for you?
We see another principle of mercy here.
Mercy requires a response.
Jesus stopped.
Was he busy?
Of course he was.
Was he on mission?
Did he have places to be?
Of course he did, but mercy requires a response.
He stopped and called to them and asked them a beautiful question.
What do you want me to do for you?
Well, look what they said.
Verse 33, they said to him, Lord, we want our eyes to be opened.
Move with compassion.
Jesus touched their eyes and immediately they regain their sight.
and followed him.
We see another principle of mercy here.
Not only does mercy require a response, but
mercy will meet one's need.
This is what this gift is all about.
Mercy will meet one's need.
I want to point out that phrase, move with compassion.
This is the saying that Jesus had a deep feeling of
empathy deep in his gut.
It's the kind of compassion that cannot be ignored or brushed off.
Have you ever seen something or seen someone in a situation or
circumstance to where it almost made you sick to your stomach.
You felt so bad for them.
This is the combation that Jesus sees here.
So what does this have to do with the church today and the gift of mercy.
Well, there are plenty of people who feel bad about the situation of others.
We don't have a lack of that.
We can sit there and say, yeah, I'll pray for you.
Yeah, I'll do this and 0 my goodness, this is just terrible.
I'm so sorry that you're going through this.
Often the action they take is to
basically gossip about their circumstance.
They mask it with a prayer request.
Baptists are terrible about this.
Have you heard of so-and-so and what they're going through?
It just breaks my heart.
You know, though, they got themselves into it, right?
I mean, it's really their fault.
Let's pray for them.
That's not mercy.
That's gossip.
You understand what I'm saying?
Those that get the mercy are almost
unable to be moved with compassion like Jesus was here in
Matthew 20 and not do something about it.
People were to get the mercy.
They see a need and they meet it.
They see someone who needs help, they help them.
They see someone who needs to be provided for it.
They provide for them.
They see someone who needs simply to be called and
just to talk to, and they do it.
How many times, listen, as a pastor, this every single week.
It's like the list gets longer and longer and longer.
But how many times have you thought, man, I should call them and pray with them?
I should call them and encourage them.
You think that's your flesh?
The flesh is exactly what happens next.
You don't.
Are you with me?
When I do this,
Okay, this this is
a call to action, okay?
All right?
I need you to mess my lapel.
Right, listen, the flesh will never say, call
a brother or sister in Christ and encourage them in the word.
But the flesh will say, you know what, they're probably busy.
As a matter of fact, you're busy.
Do it tomorrow.
And you know what happens?
We perpetually do it tomorrow.
Therefore, it never gets done.
Are y'all women this morning?
Listen, mercy will meet one's need.
Mercy sees a need.
And instead of being objective, objectively critical, those
with this gift simply do what they have to do to help.
It is a gift that requires sacrifice.
Really, this gift encompasses many other gifts we have learned about.
The gift of mercy puts action to compassion.
And guess what?
When someone manifests this gift, it's not that they don't do it to be seen.
A lot of times people don't understand it, but when people do know what's
going on, people get confused.
Why would you help them?
Why?
They don't they don't deserve it.
Exactly.
That's mercy.
To show mercy.
You may need to serve someone, give to someone, give, guide someone, or even encourage someone.
You know what is missing in the church so often?
Mercy.
How often do we see a
need and think it's not our problem?
We act like the crowd in Matthew 20.
Hush, Jesus is busy.
Someone is begging
for mercy and instead of helping them, we hush them.
The best way to start
living in mercy towards others is to start by simply stopping what you're doing.
Take a moment
to consider the need, sacrifice a moment to acknowledge someone's unfortunate
situation, hear them out and watch the Holy Spirit use you.
I can't tell you how many times.
I have been on the phone with people and they have been, they,
they go on and they go on and guess what?
That okay.
part of my job.
And at the end of it, they do this.
I don't even know why I called you.
And I tell them, I do.
You just needed someone to talk to.
And listen, hey, it's not like
I just got all that time, just, just, just, at my exposal,
but what needs to happen is disposal, not exposal.
Sorry, I knew that Michelle's going to call me out for that word, not being used, right?
But either way, listen, it's that I have to stop.
We have to stop what we're doing to show mercy.
Mercy requires a response.
We have to also understand that mercy is going to meet one's need.
Now, What
is interesting about mercy is that it is actually mentioned in one of the
greatest sermons ever preached.
Jesus in his sermon on the Mount
gave what we call beatitudes.
The beatitudes are 8 declarations of blessedness, and
Jesus gave one of the 8, included mercy.
In Matthew 5, verse 7, it says, this blessed are the merciful, For
they shall receive mercy.
I want to look at this concept of
blindness one more time.
Let's look back at the
social unacceptance of those who were blind.
Let's think about it.
They were viewed as being punished for their sin.
They were outcasts from society.
They were forbidden the service priests
because of their physical defects.
They were relegated
to begging on the side of the roads, or listen to this detail
outside the city gate.
Take that in for a moment.
There is no mistake of
why Matthew included this account of these 2 blind men.
In another accountant John, there was a blind
man who was blind from birth to show his disciples, we already read about it a little bit.
But to show his disciples his power and glory.
Jesus healed this blind beggar with the spit and the mud
that he wiped upon his eyes and say, go wash it off.
And when he washed it off and the mud came off of his eyes, he could see.
Now, remember, the Pharisees did not appreciate this.
Jesus just so happened to do this on the Sabbath.
That was a big no no in the religious world.
And so they began to investigate.
They went to the blind man and asked him.
They said, what's going on?
What is this?
The text kind of indicates that they weren't really believing
that he was actually blind.
This is just a trick of Jesus.
This is just him trying to get people to follow him.
Surely he did not actually heal a blind man.
They even went to the people that
he knew that knew him and because he had been there his whole life begging,
and they went to his parents and said, is
your son actually blind?
And like, he's been blind from birth.
I don't know what to tell you.
As a matter of fact, his parents even kind
of said, hey, look, just go talk to him because they
knew that if they were too attached to what was going on, they could be outcasted as well.
So they finally went back to this blind man who was once blind.
And they start to investigate him and question him,
hey, listen, we don't really believe this.
They went back to the man who
was healed and this is one of my favorite responses in all the Bible.
John 9, 24, through 25
says this, so a 2nd time they called the man who had been blind and said to him, give glory to God.
We know that this man is a sinner.
In other words, they're saying, hey, they're trying they're trying to change who Jesus is.
We know that Jesus is a sinner, so how could he heal you?
And look what this man said.
He then answered, whether he is a sinner, I do not know.
One thing I do know, that though I
was blind, now I see.
You
might be thinking, what does that have to do with me?
Well, aside from Christ, we are spiritually blinded.
First Corinthians 2.14, but the natural man
receiveth not the things of the Spirit of God.
For they are foolishness unto him, neither can he know them
because they are spiritually discerned.
2 Corinthians 4, verse 4, in whose case the God of
this world has blinded the minds of the unbelieving so
they might not see the light of the gospel, the glory of Christ, who is the image of God.
First John 211, but the one who
hates his brother is in darkness and walks in the darkness and
does not know where he is going.
Why?
Because the darkness has blinded his eyes.
Without Christ, you and I are blind.
Wandering this earth like a beggar.
Remember what these 2 blind men did
in Matthew 20, they cried out to Jesus.
Does this sound familiar?
Romans 10, 13, for whosoever
shall call upon the name of Lord, shall be saved.
What did they cry out?
Notice the verbiage.
Lord, have mercy on us, son of David.
Romans 10, 9, and 10, that thou shalt confess with
thy mouth, the Lord Jesus, and shalt believe in
thy heart that God raised them from the dead.
Thou shalt be safe with the heart, man, believing unto righteousness.
And with the mouth confession is made unto salvation.
This is a beautiful picture of salvation.
What happened to these blind people, God healed.
Well, they will welcome back into the holy things of God.
They were able to enter back into the city gates.
They were no longer beggars, but they were citizens.
They were
placed in the fellowship.
Now listen, I'm almost done,
but I really need you to pay attention here.
Remember, aside from God's, you're blinded.
I'm blinded.
Amen.
Do not miss this church in 1st Peter 2.
7 through 10.
And it really it really should open your
eyes to the truth of who we are in Christ.
Look at this precious value starting verse 7.
Then it's for you who believe, but for those who this believe.
The stone which the builders rejected, this became
the very cornerstone.
And a stone of stumbling and a rock of offense,
for they stumble because they are disobedient to the word,
and to this doom, they were also appointed, but you.
Now, he's talking to those who believe.
But you are a chosen race.
A royal priesthood, a holy
nation, a people for God's own possession,
so that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who
has called you out of darkness into his
marvelous light.
For you once were not a people, but now you are
the people of God.
You had not received mercy.
But now you have received mercy.
And now because we have obtained such mercy,
God desires us to show mercy to others as well.
Church, God
held for me what I deserve to show compassion on me through Jesus.
And may we do the same to others.
And when we do, the Bible also tells us, do it cheerfully.
Don't
do it like it's a burden.
Listen, we got to stop making the things of God a burden.
Listen, doesn't mean it's not difficult.
Does it mean we're not tired?
It doesn't mean we're not ready to give up, but what it means is we have
to keep our mind on Christ understanding.
This is literally, physically, spiritually, why we
are still yet on this earth is to serve him.
So
as we close this portion of text in Romans 12, I want to understand, I
want us to understand the way Paul wrote this and why.
Look again at Romans
12, 6 to 8.
Since we have gifts that differ according to the grace given to us, Each
of us is to exercise them accordingly, if prophecy according to proportion
of his faith, if service in his serving, or he who
teaches in his teaching, or he that exhorts in his exhortation,
he who gives with liberality, he who leads with
diligence, he who shows mercy with cheerfulness.
Notice
that he is not explaining these gifts, but rather simply encouraging the use of these gifts.
Now, we've explained them because we've looked at the concept of each one.
But Paul, when he's writing to the saints in Rome,
He's not expositing.
He's saying, you know what to do, just do it.
I want to
read to you an explanation from the home of New Testament commentary.
I mean, this got me this got me fired up right here.
Listen to this.
The gifts Paul mentioned in Romans are
presented in such a way to make themselves explanatory.
It is as if Paul is answering questions
from those new to the idea of spiritual gifts.
Paul, what should I do if I'm a prophet prophesy?
but only by faith.
What if my gift is serving then serve?
What about teaching?
Teach, encouraging?
Encourage someone, giving to others?
Give generously, leading, start leading, showing
mercy, stop frowning.
People who need mercy also need good cheer.
In other words, the implication seems to be that
we are not to wait around for instructions or for
a mystical move, the spirit in order to minister to the body of Christ.
We are to do that which is obvious to us and
which we feel compelled and capable of doing.
That is how the church functions.
To that.
I say, what are you doing?
How has God gifted you?
Listen, I
just I just want to say this and we're about to be done.
Oh, we're so close to the end.
It's not even funny.
But I want to I want to
encourage, but also challenge you in this.
God has never called anyone.
to not serve
in the church.
Not one person.
You say, well, preacher, I'm,
I'm just old and I can't really do much.
Yes, you can.
It may look different than what you once could do.
But you can serve.
If not, why you're here.
I
don't want to offend you, but if not, why you're here.
Well, preacher, I'm just so
new to the faith that I'm just going to sit around for the next 10
to 25 years and learn about God's word
and then maybe one day I'll get to where I can serve.
Are you kidding me?
People need to hear about Jesus right now today.
People need encouraging today.
need to be led today.
Listen, hey, we don't know about tomorrow, but we do know about today.
Well, preacher, you know, I
just feel like someone else should do it.
I guarantee if I went to them, you know what they say?
They feel like you should do it.
You know, it would be cool if we just all did.
And
you say, I'm just not gifted.
Well, then that means you're lost.
I
want you to think about that for a second.
You tell me you don't have
a spiritual gift, I'm going to tell you, you need Jesus.
Because the Bible says that when you have Jesus,
you have the Holy Spirit.
Therefore, you're gifted.
So
church, what are you doing for Christ?
There's
a thing going around where there's so much church hurt.
And I'm not going to ask you to raise your
hand, but I know we've all been there.
Can I tell you, the church has
not hurt anyone more than Jesus Christ.
Yet he's still faithful to us.
Yet he still blesses us.
Yet he still died for us.
He shows us mercy.
Listen, I don't want to undermine
or discourage you from thinking that your church art was not
valid and legit.
There are bad things that happen when people come together that are broken and sinful.
But I need you to know something.
The enemy
could have caused that church hurt knowing that he'd stop you.
Stop you from what?
Stop you from using the gift that God gave you.
For the building up of his church.
Why?
Because you have bitterness towards this person or resentment towards that person.
Or this person way, long time ago,
talked about your kid, or this happened, or that happened.
Listen, can I tell you something?
Hey, church hurt.
You know what church hurt should be?
Church, church should be a momentary lapse in judgment, reconciliation takes place.
We keep on keeping on.
That's what church should be.
But you
know what church heard is happening in our culture?
It's become almost like a generational curse.
Why don't you go to church?
Wow, well, my grandparents used to go to church, but they got hurt,
and so they didn't bring my parents.
Now I don't go.
Do you see where it could go?
You know how to combat that?
Serve.
Love each other.
Show mercy on each other.
I'm gonna tell you right now, I'm gonna mess up.
I'm gonna probably hurt your feelings, and I don't mean to.
Sometimes I didn't mean to, and I need to confess that.
But listen, hey, I can't we can't stay there.
Just like I want to show mercy to you.
I need you to show mercy to me.
Because God's shown mercy to all this.
It has bound eyes closed over this place.
I just wonder what the Holy Spirit's doing right now.